catster.com 2015-06-01

# privacy policy | catster

Catster.com is a website for sharing cat facts and photos with other cat lovers. It is operated by i-5 Publishing, LLC, a privately held company based in Irvine, CA, USA. Your personal privacy is EXTREMELY important to us. This Privacy Policy explains how we collect and use your personal identifying information. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully, and if you have any questions, please feel free to contact us. 

By using Catster.com, you consent to the collection and use of your personal information as outlined in the Privacy Policy. From time to time, we may update the Privacy Policy and we will post a notice of significant changes on the site. You should visit this page periodically to review any such changes to the Privacy Policy. 

**The information we collect**

When you register to become a member of Catster.com, we collect your name, email address and optionally your hometown, state and country. When you register your cat we collect the information you want to share about that canine, name, age, likes, dislikes, sex ,etc. Your name and email will never be shared, rented, bartered or sold with other users or third-party companies. All information entered about your cat(s) will only be used by Catster.com to display on the site and will never be shared, rented, bartered, sold or exchanged any other purposeful manner. The website, however, is accessible by anyone with an internet connection and a web browser, which means that any words and photos you post can be copied by any other internet user. That is the nature of the internet and though we discourage anyone from abusing that option, it is something that must be noted 

In order to provide the best possible service and detect and correct site errors, we collect aggregate information about use of the site (such as which page are most often viewed) and we collect information about your computer, such as such as browser type, browser language, and IP address. This information as well is never shared with anyone. 

**How we use your information**

Your human name and email will never be shared with anyone in anyway. If you chose to enter your human hometown, state or country that information will be displayed in any of your cat's web pages on the site, but the cat page does not share any other personal information or allow access to it. Currently we use your submitted email to notify you of Feline Friends friend requests, but the requestor never sees that email. When a user submits a Tell-A-Friend form we never store or copy any of the sender or recipient emails for any period of time. 

We work with third parties who provide services, including but not limited to website hosting, e-commerce affiliation, data analysis, emailing and other services of an administrative nature. Personally identifiable information, is shared with such third parties for the purpose of providing such services. Further, we may use selected reputable third parties for marketing, targeting and analysis purposes. Some of these third parties may be given access to some, or all, of the information that you provide to us and may use cookies or other tracking technologies in connection with providing their services. To the extent that we provide your personally identifiable information to such third parties, we seek to restrict their ability to use such information for their own marketing purposes; however, we cannot be responsible for the privacy policies or practices of such third parties. 

The biographical information you enter about your cat(s) is instantly available to all other users of the site. Catster does not claim rights for the pictures uploaded or the text information you add to the site. Please note, however, that Catster.com is a public site and thus all photos and information you provide are available to anyone with internet access. Due to the nature of the internet, it is impossible for Catster.com to be a protectorate of your cat'(s') facts and photos, so you should never post a photo or fact that you do not now or ever want someone else to have access to. 

**Legal requests**

You understand and agree that Catster.com may access, preserve, and disclose your personal information and the contents of your account if required to do so by law or in a good faith belief that such access preservation or disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process, such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute, or court order, or to protect the rights and property of Catster.com, its affiliates or the public. 

**Controlling your personal information**

You have complete control of the information you submit to Catster. You may at anytime edit any information or remove your cat and personal accounts entirely. Catster.com only requires a user give a valid email while you have an account so we may contact you. 

Please note, we reserve the right to transfer your submitted information in the event of a transfer of ownership of Catster.com, such as acquisition by or merger with another company. In such an event, Catster.com will notify you before information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. 

**Cookies**

We send "cookies" to your computer and use such cookies as described here. A cookie is a piece of data that identifies you as a unique user. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service and make the service easier to use for our members. We do this by storing user preferences in cookies and by tracking user trends - for example, we use cookies to allow you to automatically log in to the service after the first user session. 

Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. Be aware, however, that some parts of Catster.com may not function properly if you refuse cookies. 

**External links**

Catster.com may contain links to other web sites. These other sites maintain their own policies regarding cookies and the collection and use of personal information. 

**Security**

We use industry standard security measures to protect your information so that it is not made available to unauthorized parties. If you have any questions regarding which measures and techniques we use, feel free to contact us. 

**Contacting Us**

You can always contact us at any time by email at catsters@catster.com . 

Our mailing address is:  
Catster  
i-5 Publishing, LLC  
2017 Mission Street, 2nd Floor  
San Francisco, CA 94110  

**Unsubscribing**

You can easily unsubscribe at any time. In any email you recieve from www.catster.com there will be an "unsubscribe" or "Opt-out" link in the footer of the email. Clicking on that link will take you immediately to a page where you can unsubscribe or globally opt-out from all email correspondence from www.catster.com. 

Additionaly, members can always adjust their email preference, including unsubscribing, by going to http://www.catster.com/account/account_email_pref.php. 

Remember, all emails can be unsubscribed from immediately by clicking the "unsubscribe" or "opt-out" link in any email.

Have other questions? 

Again, feel free to contact us any time, and if you have further questions about Catster.com.
